<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ods-analysis on Codelibrary</title>
    <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/tags/ods-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ods-analysis on Codelibrary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 14:46:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/tags/ods-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Heatmaps with CSS Grid</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/heatmaps-custom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 14:46:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/heatmaps-custom/</guid>
      <description>We consider the usage of ods-adv-analysis as a prerequisite of this resource. Documentation available here
  Did you see ? Heatmaps with Vega-lite
 If Vega-lite does not satisfy your needs, for advanced usages, you can create heatmaps by hand with only HTML and CSS Grid.
Keep in mind that, for heatmaps or bubblemaps, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to adapt the display depending on the values, axis, and legends.
For example, if the aggregation is too large to be displayed in cells, using ods-tooltip could be a nice way to display the value while hovering with the cursor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heatmaps with Vega-Lite</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/heatmaps-vegalite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 14:46:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/heatmaps-vegalite/</guid>
      <description>Vega-Lite is a high-level grammar of interactive graphics. It provides a concise, declarative JSON syntax to create an expressive range of visualizations for data analysis and presentation.
ods-vega-lite-chart widget, in combinaison with ods-adv-analysis to get the data, allows adding Vega-Lite charts into your pages.
This first resource is an introduction and pre-requisite to understand key concepts of Vega-Lite within ODS.
 We consider the usage of ods-adv-analysis as a pre-requisite of this resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ods-analysis, quick intro</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The technical documentation says :
This widget exposes the results of an analysis (as an object containing a results array and optionally an aggregations object) in a variable available in the scope. It can be used with AngularJS&amp;rsquo;s ngRepeat to simply build a table of analysis results.
Normal people would say :
Ods-analysis is the way to get the values behind a chart ! What you can do with a chart, you can do the same with ods-analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
