<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apps on Codelibrary</title>
    <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apps on Codelibrary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alerts on the State of your Data With Zapier</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/zapier-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/zapier-data/</guid>
      <description>Create alerts on datasets and be notified in real time when an update or a new element is produced
Description   The context
You are a reuser of a number of datasets or several data portals, whether your own or those of other organizations. You need to be informed when new data are published or modified, when a problem arises on any number of them, or when real-time data are not updated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 for US Counties</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/covid-us-counties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/covid-us-counties/</guid>
      <description>Create a live COVID-19 for your county, city etc. with local data.
Description   The context
You have a regularly updated source of data about COVID-19 for your region (e.g. County or City) that that reflects information not available nationwide. You want to keep the population updated on the number of cases, the number of occupied hospital beds etc. in their surroundings. You want to make the data available for nation-wide aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Election Results Visualization</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/election/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/election/</guid>
      <description>Combine several datasets regarding election results and give your citizens a 360° representation of the share of votes across your territory.
Description   The context
Elections are always a highlight for you and your constituents. To make your citizens want to follow the details of the live votes on your portal and facilitate the understanding of the results, you will need to offer them legible and engaging content.
The service</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Form Survey Results Visualization</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/google-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/google-form/</guid>
      <description>Automate the result display from your collaborative surveys by connecting Google Form to your Opendatasoft portal.
Description   The context
You are preparing a survey and you need to visualize the results in a legible and structured way, as well as enrich them with other data. Google Form allows easy collection of these results, but not their advanced visualization or comparison with other data. Integrating Google Form with the Opendatasoft platform can help you take advantage of both tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KPI Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/kpi-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/kpi-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>Create personalized dashboards to measure the performance of your actions and highlight your concrete achievements
Description   The context
Whether you are a community or a company, your goal is to provide an ever higher quality of service to your citizens or customers. For that, you need to evaluate the accomplishment of the actions carried out by your organization. These performance indicators reflect your strategic plan objectives, or your municipality’s political program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your IoT data speak</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/iot/</guid>
      <description>Build dynamic and easy to read visualization on your sensors data and connected equipments
Description   The context
Smart sorting bins and energy meters, traffic surveillance cameras, fleets of geolocated vehicles … the connected equipment is multiplying within the territories, producing a considerable amount of data in real time. Gross, voluminous and complex, this IoT data often remains indecipherable for the human eye.
The service
Opendatasoft provides you with a visualization model fully designed to represent, understand and analyze all your IoT data, regardless of their source and format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notify your users on your data updates</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/zapier-notify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/zapier-notify/</guid>
      <description>Send alerts to your users when you perform operation on your data or when critic threshold are reached
Description   The context
You are a reuser of a number of datasets or several data portals, whether your own or those of other organizations. You need to be informed when new data are published or modified, when a problem arises on any number of them, or when real-time data are not updated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanitation Inspection Transparency</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/sanitary-inspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/sanitary-inspection/</guid>
      <description>Created by the Ministry of Agriculture, the Alim&amp;rsquo;Confiance app facilitates the sharing of hygiene check results carried out in food establishments.
Description   The Use Case
The General Directorate of Food (DGAL) carries out thousands of health inspections each year in restaurants, bakeries, chocolate makers, supermarkets and other numerous food shops in France. To increase transparency around inspection data and thus enable the population to make an informed choice of where to go to eat, the DGAL has created the Alim&amp;rsquo;Confiance app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Canteen Menu Displays</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/canteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/canteen/</guid>
      <description>Save school officials time: give them a printable menu model containing up-to-date information
Description   The context
French schools display their canteen menus each week either so that it can be read by students and their parents. In the majority of cases, the municipality sets the composition of the meals then sends the information to school establishments who then have to reprocess the information into a spreadsheet or a word processor in order to then print and display it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Diagnostic with Waze</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/waze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/apps/waze/</guid>
      <description>Enrich your own data with traffic data and observe in real-time the state of traffic across your territory
Description   The context
Waze’s Connected Citizens Program promotes pooling resources: Waze provides its partners with real-time data on incidents and trouble zones slowing down traffic as signaled by drivers, while its partners give Waze data in real time on the closures of certain roads, ongoing road work, and major accidents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
