<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aggregation on Codelibrary</title>
    <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/tags/aggregation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aggregation on Codelibrary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 14:46:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/tags/aggregation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Heatmaps with CSS Grid</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/heatmaps-custom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 14:46:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/heatmaps-custom/</guid>
      <description>We consider the usage of ods-adv-analysis as a prerequisite of this resource. Documentation available here
  Did you see ? Heatmaps with Vega-lite
 If Vega-lite does not satisfy your needs, for advanced usages, you can create heatmaps by hand with only HTML and CSS Grid.
Keep in mind that, for heatmaps or bubblemaps, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to adapt the display depending on the values, axis, and legends.
For example, if the aggregation is too large to be displayed in cells, using ods-tooltip could be a nice way to display the value while hovering with the cursor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heatmaps with Vega-Lite</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/heatmaps-vegalite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 14:46:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/heatmaps-vegalite/</guid>
      <description>Vega-Lite is a high-level grammar of interactive graphics. It provides a concise, declarative JSON syntax to create an expressive range of visualizations for data analysis and presentation.
ods-vega-lite-chart widget, in combinaison with ods-adv-analysis to get the data, allows adding Vega-Lite charts into your pages.
This first resource is an introduction and pre-requisite to understand key concepts of Vega-Lite within ODS.
 We consider the usage of ods-adv-analysis as a pre-requisite of this resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KPI Generator</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/generators/kpi-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:05:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/generators/kpi-generator/</guid>
      <description>EXPERIMENTAL
 This generator builds a KPI wall.
With specific parameters for each KPI card, it will compare values, compute a progression or analyse how your data evolved over time on a specific period.
Like any other generator, it deals with all the complexity of manipulating dates, refining specific context, computing and comparing aggregation etc&amp;hellip;
As the code is complex, and the resource might be difficult to reuse, we consider it experimental and share it in an early stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animations</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 20:57:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/animation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KPIs</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/components/kpis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:21:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/components/kpis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static maps, a quick introduction</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/svg-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 15:57:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/svg-maps/</guid>
      <description>When your goal is to share a precise analysis of a theme, such as employment or demography, for given administrative territories, you may want to disable all interactions with the map. You will even probably want to have overseas territories right next to the other territories in order to visualize immediately how the measurement varies across these administrative areas.
In this situation, you might prefer a static colored picture over a classic map widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chart samples</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/charts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observatory</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/page-templates/observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/page-templates/observatory/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ods-adv-analysis</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-adv-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-adv-analysis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ods-aggregation</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-aggregation/</guid>
      <description>The technical documentation says :
This widget exposes the results of an aggregation function over a context&amp;hellip; The result is exposed into a new variable that you can use in other widgets or directly in your HTML.
More concretely :
It computes a function like the sum, average, minimum, maximum etc.. over a numerical field. Depending on the context parameters, if filtered (queries, refines, etc&amp;hellip;) it will compute the aggregation on a subset of the records, if not, on the entire dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ods-analysis, quick intro</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The technical documentation says :
This widget exposes the results of an analysis (as an object containing a results array and optionally an aggregations object) in a variable available in the scope. It can be used with AngularJS&amp;rsquo;s ngRepeat to simply build a table of analysis results.
Normal people would say :
Ods-analysis is the way to get the values behind a chart ! What you can do with a chart, you can do the same with ods-analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ods-color-gradient &#43; ods-map : a choropleth alternative</title>
      <link>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-color-gradient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codelibrary.opendatasoft.com/widget-tricks/ods-color-gradient/</guid>
      <description>This map rendering technique allows to display on a map colored shaped based on the aggregation of a different dataset.
One dataset contains the data to make some statistical computation (Avg, sum, counting of numerical fields) and one dataset contains geographical information (geo shapes).
The technique is very similar to a join at processing time, to enrich statistical data with geographical data. The only prerequisit is, like for a regular join, having a shared key between datasets to make the numerical aggregation match its geo shape.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
